Guide to the Ann Lovett papers, 1979-2015 RL.11257
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ann Lovett papers
1979-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11257
9 Linear Feet
Ann Lovett is an artist who teaches at the State University of New York at New Paltz. This collection documents her artistic and academic career with a focus on her work in the book arts.
Biographical / Historical
Ann Lovett is an artist who works in books, photographs, and prints. She also works as a professor of Art at the State University of New York at New Paltz. She holds a B.S. in Studio Art from Skidmore College and an M.F.A from the Tyler School of Art at Temple University. Her work is represented in national and international collections, and has been widely exhibited. She has been awarded a number of national and international grants, fellowships, and residencies.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Ann Lovett papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Collection Overview
The collection contains materials documenting Lovett's artistic and academic career, including artists' book production materials and photographs.
Related Materials
The library holds a number of Ann Lovett's artist books, which can be discovered with an author search in the catalog.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chiefly in chronological order.
Artists' books; Artists' books -- United States; Artists' books by women; Women artists -- New York (State); Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Lovett, Ann
- 1979-1989 (Box 1)
- Dorsky Show, 1990 (Box 2)
- 1991-1995 (Box 2)
- Hospital Project, 1995-1997; 2 folders (Box 2)
- 1996-2002 (Box 3)
- 2003-2011 (Box 4)
- In Retrospect, 2010 (Box 4)
- 2013-2015 (Box 5)
- Resume, 2015 (Box 5)
- Negatives, circa 1979-2015; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Photos, circa 1979-2015; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Family Histories, circa 1979-2015 (Box 5)
- Family Story binder, 1990s (Box 5)
- Posters, circa 1979-2015 (Box 6)